Gregory Pincus Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Speech, Article, and Book File, 1926-1967 (Box 135-146)
  - 1963
    - 'Clinical Control of Fertility;" "Advances in Chemistry"
    - "Contraception Using Oral Progestin-Estrogin Medication," with Garcia, Celso-Ramon, and Satterchwaite, A. P.
    - "Effects of Estrous Cycle Variations and Exogenous Steroid"
    - "Hormones on the Production and Secretion Corticostinone by the Rat Adrenal," with Hioai"
    - "Effects of Reseopine on Gonadolropin Induced Ovulation in Immature Rats," with Hopkins, T. F.
    - "Frontiers in Methods of Fertility Control," American Association for the Advancement of Science symposium
    - "Homograft Implants of Young Testes, Ovaries and Ovotestes in the Intact Female Chick," with Erickson, A. E.
    - "Hormonal Steroids and Ceruical Pathology," with Garcia, Celso-Ramon
    - "Insensitivity of Fowl Testes to Cadmium," with Erickson, A. E.
    - "In Vitro Exposure of Rabbit Ova to Estrogens," with Ketchel, M. M.
    - Ladies Home Journal
    - "Metabolic Changes Induced in Elderly Patients with a Cholesterol Lowering Resin, Cholestyramine," with Gherondache, C. N. (Box 142)
    - "Ovulation Inhibition by Progestin-Estrogen Combination," with Garcia, Celso-Ramon
    - "Pharmacology of Reproduction & Sterility" with Fridhandler, L.
    - Review of Steroid Drugs, by G.P.J. of American Chemical Society
  - 1964
    - "Biologically Active Substances Affecting Gonadotrophin Induced Ovulation in Immature Rats," with France, E. S.
    - "Clinical Considerations with Oral Hormone Control of Human
      - Fertility," with Garcia, Celson-Ramon
    - "Drugs Used in Control of Reproduction," with Bialy, G.
    - 'Effect of Pregnant Mare's Serum"
    - "Gonadotrophin, Estradiol, & Progesterone on Superovulation in the Immature Rat," with Wyss, H.
    - "Effect of Cychic Administration of Certain Progestin-Estrogen Combinations on the 24-Hour Radio Iodine Thyroid Uptake," with Frias, Z., Iricarry, S., Janes, R. T. L., and Paniagua, M.
    - "Effect of Time Interval Following a Single Injection of Estradiol"
    - "Benzoate on Carbonic Anhydrase Activity and Protein Content of Immature Mouse Uteri"
    - "Estrogens and the Transport of Ova in the Rat," with Banik, U. K.
    - "Further Studies on Implantation Inhibitors," with Banik, U. K., and Jacques, J.
    - "In Virto Effect of Estrone and Brady Kinin on a Nuclear Abnormality in a Hamster Ascites Tumor," with Stevens, D. F.
    - "Long-Term Use of Progestin-Estrogen Combinations," with
      - Garcia, Celso-Ramon
    - "Mechanism of Oral Contraception;" Symposium on Agents Affecting Fertility
    - "Metabolic Fate of Orally Administered H3-Norethynodrel and H3 Norethindrone in Humans," with Arai, D. S., and Golab, Layne
    - "Ovarian Steroids, Analogues and Homologues," World Health
      - Organization
    - "Physiological Effects of Cyclic Administration of Profestin-Estrogen Combinations"
    - "Risk of Carcinogensis"
    - "Serum Enzymes in the Menstrul Cycle," with Donayre, J.
    - "Some Biological Properties of a Urinary Norethynodrel Metabolite," with Baily, G., and Layne, D. S.
    - "Studies on Vaginal, Cervical, and Uterine Histology," with
      - Garcia, Celso-Ramon; Seaview Symposium
    - Untitled paper by Pincus and Barzilia, D.
  - 1965 (Box 143)
    - "Combined Estrogen-Progestin Therapy in Contraception"
    - "Control of Conception by Hormal Steroids," American Association for the Advancement of Science
    - Control of Fertility
      - Correspondence
      - Author index
      - Preface
      - Chapters 1-11, draft, (11 folders)
      - Chapters 12-13, draft and references, (2 folders) (Box 144)
      - Proof, (3 folders)
      - Tables and figures
      - Typescript, partial, annotated
    - "Effects of Rat Hypothalamic and Cerebral Tiddue on PMS-Induces Ovulation," with Hopkins, T. F. (Box 145)
    - "Endocrine Factors in the Control of Fertility in Mammals"
    - "Hormonal Steroids and Preimplantation Stages," Ciba Foundation
    - "Long-Term Effects of Oral Contraception," with Garcia, Celson-Ramon, and Locanora
    - "Modification of Embryonic Development of Reproductive and Lympnoid Organs in the Chick," with Erickson, A. E.
    - "Radioactivity in the Milk of Subjects Receiving Radioactive
      - 19-Norsteroids," with Bialy, G., Layne, D., Paniagua, M., and Williams, K. I.
    - Steroid Drugs, vol. 2
    - "Steroidal Inhibitors of a Mitosis-Inducing System In Vitro," with Gordon
  - 1966
    - "Action of Hormonal Steroids on the Hypothalama-Pituitary Ovarian Axis"
    - "Control of Fertility in Mammals by Hormonal Steroids," editorial for Notes on Teratology
    - "Effects of Hormonal Steroids Upon Ovarian and Endometrial Cycles - Long-Term Effects, with Garcia, Celso-Ramon, Rocamora, Hector, and Merrill, A.
    - "Experimental Studies of Fertility Control by Hormonal Steroids in Mammals"
    - "Long-term effects of Oral Contraception," with Garcia, Celso-Ramon, and Rocamora, Hector (Box 146)
    - "Metabolism and Secretion of Aidosterone in Elderly Subjects," with Flood, C., Gherondache, C., Tait, J. F., and Willoughby, S.
    - "Metabolism of 17-1 Soaldosterone and Aldosterone," with Flood, C., Tait, J. F., and Wiloughby, S.
    - "Radioactivity in the Milk of Subjects Receiving Radioactive 19-Norsteroids"
    - "Some Activities of a Potent Steroidal Anti-Estrogen," with Bialy, G., and Merrill, Ann P.
    - "Studies on the Mechanism of Secretion of Adrenal Corticostero Following Morphine Administration to Female Rats," with Hirai, Sekiyama
  - 1967
    - Autobiography
    - "Effects of Hypophysectomy on Corticosteroidogenesis
      - of Rat Adrenal in Vivo," with Matsuba, Shima
    - "Hormones and Phosphatase Activity," with Bialy, G.
    - "Influence of Hypophysectomy, Adrenalectomy, Orchiectomy" Administration of Various Steroids on the Growth of Transplanted Prostatic Carcinoma in the Rat," with Dowling, and Gherondache, C.
    - "Metabolism of.... in Young and Elderly Men," with Baxter, M. N., Malhotra, K. K., and Romanoff, L. P.
    - "Population Growth and Age Composition"
    - "Steroid Labile Reproductive Processes in Mammals"
    - "Young Memorial Volume on Reproduction and Sexual Behavior"
    - Speech, in French, by Pincus on endocrinology
- Research Material, 1933-1967 (Box 147-169)
  - Research Data, 1933-1967 (Box 147-160)
    Notebooks and papers containing research data, records of experiments, and illustrations relating to scientific studies by Pincus and his staff. Much of this material was labeled by Pincus.
    - List of publications (Box 147)
    - Manuscript tables for new paper on 19-nor cpds.
    - Rabbit egg culture and hormone effects, 1933
    - Experiment book, 1933
    - Diabetes, hormones, sterilization, 1934-1937
    - Estrogen color reactions, 1935-1936
    - Rabbit and human eggs, 1935-1936 (Box 148)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1935-1944
    - Egg transplantation methods and rabbits recovered, circa 1936
    - Biology, vitamin C, 1936
    - Ovum culture data, 1936
    - Egg culture and transplantation, 1936
    - Rabbit egg experiments, 1936
    - Rat and rabbit uteri, circa 1937
    - Progesterone uteri, circa 1937 (Box 149)
    - Egg data, 1938
    - Monkey urines, 1939
    - Pituitary gonadotrophin assay, 1939
    - Egg cultures, 1939-1940
    - Colorimetric determination of androsterone and dehydroandrosterone, 1939-1940
    - Data on control and schizophrenic subjects under cold stress, 1940s
    - Pituitary purification, 1940
    - Uterine enzymes, 1940
    - Human endometrium respirations, 1940
    - Urinary color reactions in cancer cases, 1940 (Box 150)
    - Incubation of tissues with added hormones, 1940-1941
    - Color reactions in cancer and noncancer urines, 1940-1941
    - Steroid exretion in cases of cancer and in control subjects, 1940-1941
    - Egg cultures, 1940-1941
    - Deep freezing of semen and sperm, 1940-1942
    - Fatigue data, 1941
    - Hormone assays, pituitary; experiments 1941-1942 (Box 151)
    - Egg culture experiments, 1941-1943
    - Pilot fatigue studies, 1941-1943
    - Bioassays, 1941-1943
    - Purification of gonadotrophic hormones, 1942
    - Adrenal cold stress, 1943
    - Urinary steroids, 1943
    - Urinary steroid analysis, 1943-1944
    - Stress studies, 1944
    - Adrenal perfusion, 1944
    - Cholesterol, 1944
    - Industrial fatigue data, 1944 (Box 152)
    - Androgen and estrogen assays, 1944-1945
    - Follett, Hadidian, Pirie, notebooks I-VI, 1944-1945, (2 folders)
    - Hadidian and Pirie, notebook, 1945
    - Bioassay, 1945-1946
    - Cow-egg data, 1945-1948
    - M. Cook notebook, circa 1945
    - Hyaluronic acid, 1946
    - Hyaluronidased data, circa 1946
    - Hadidian, Rose, Oginsky, notebook, 1946
    - Notebooks, with Hadidian, 1946 (Box 153)
    - Vaginal smears, 1946
    - U.S. submarine base data, 1946
    - Antiestrogens from plant sources, circa 1946
    - A. E. Follett, notebooks, 1946-1947
    - Bioassay notebooks, 1946-1947
    - Follett, Hadidian, notebook, 1947 (Box 154)
    - Ovarian transplantation, 1947
    - Bioassay notebooks, 1947-1949
    - Russian translations, 1947
    - Aging studies, 1947-1949
    - Adrenal response to hormones, 1947-1949
    - Antihyaluronidase experiments, 1948
    - Sodium retention assay, 1948-1949 (Box 155)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1948-1949
    - Lactone data, 1948-1949
    - L. Stewart, notebooks, 1948-1950
    - R. D. Stewart, notebooks, 1948-1950
    - On mink, Hammond, Jr., 1948-1949
    - Steroids and the pituitary assays, 1949 (Box 156)
    - Macy conference notes, 1949-1950
    - Notebooks of experiments, 1950
    - Slides, 1950
    - Corticosteroids and electrolyte excretion,1949, undated
    - Progesterone, 1951
    - Experiments, 1951-1953
    - Progesterone project data, 1953-1957 (Box 157)
    - Fertility, rabbit experiments, 1953-1955
    - Studies on the stress of flying in air force personnel, 1955-1956
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1958-1959, (2 folders)
    - Aging studies, 1959
    - West Point Planned Parenthood Federation of America conference, rabbits, 1959
    - Puerto Rico, Haiti, data, 1961-1964
    - Cholesterol determinations 1962
    - Gerontology data, 1962
    - Animal data, 1962
    - Assay reports and results, 1964
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1965 (Box 158)
    - Research and lecture notes, 1967
    - Lantern slides, 1967, (3 folders)
    - Miscellaneous data, undated
    - Pregnenolone and industrial fatigue (Box 159)
    - Steroid lactones and estrogens dialysed against protein
    - Stress related changes in psychotic and normal subjects
    - Steroid medication in arthritic patients
    - Stress studies in schizophrenic patents and normals controls
    - Lymphocytes and ascorbic acids in animals and in man
    - Urinary pigment c fraction in cancer
    - Blood steroids
    - Diketone work
    - Miscellaneous notes, (5 folders)
    - Chang's data on anti-fertility tests in rats
    - Miscellaneous research date (Box OV 160)
  - Scientific Staff Reports, 1944-1962 (Box 161-169)
    Reports and memoranda of research projects by members of Pincus's staff.
    - 1944-1946 (Box 161)
      - Research reports
      - Steroid Experiments
      - Elmadjian, Fred, 1946-1954
    - 1947
      - Research reports
      - Roberts, Sidney, and Szego, Clara M.
    - 1948
      - Research reports
      - Carlo, J. 1948-1954
      - Elmadjian, Fred, 1948-1959
      - Freeman, H., 1948-1954
      - Hechter, Oscar, 1948-1954, (2 folders)
      - Jeanloz, Roger, 1948 (Box 162)
      - Jacobson, R., 1946-1954
      - Lamson, Ed, 1946-1953
      - Levy, H., 1946-1956
      - Levy, L,. 1948-1952
      - Scola, R. N., 1948-1952
      - Stewart, R. D., 1948-1950
      - Weiss, I,. 1948
      - Werthesson, N., 1948-1950
    - 1949
      - Research reports
      - Chang, M. C., 1949-1955
      - Gut, M. 1949-1954
      - Romanoff, E. 1949-1954 (Box 163)
      - Romanoff, L. 1949-1954
    - 1950-1951
      - Research reports
      - Hammond, John, 1950
      - Dorfman, R., 1951-1959
      - Fish, A. 1951-1954
      - Hammond, John 1950
      - Hoyano, M., 1951-1954
      - McNiven, N., 1951-1954
      - Meyer, A., 1951-1955 (Box 164)
      - Rubin, B., 1951-1954
      - Schenker, V., 1951-1953
      - Small, M., 1951-1952
    - 1952
      - Research reports
      - Borrell, S., 1952-1953
      - Savard, K., 1952-1954
      - Slocombe, A., 1952-1953
      - Stone, D., 1952-1954
      - Todd, D., 1952-1954
    - 1953-1954
      - Research reports
      - Aleksandrowicz, G., 1953-1954 (Box 165)
      - Ballan, J. M., 1953
      - Bloch, E., 1953-1957
      - Dorfman, A,. 1953-1958, (2 folders)
      - Hope, J., 1953-1954
      - Pincus, G,. 1953-1955
      - Rosenkrantz, H., 1953-1954
      - Schwenk, E., 1953-1954
      - Ungar, F., 1953-1954
      - Zilinski, A., 1953-1957
      - Bergen, J., 1954
      - Burnstein, S., 1954-1955
      - Choiniere, J., 1954
      - Fish, A., 1954-1958
      - Forchielli, E., 1954
      - Freeman, Harry, 1954-1956
      - Levy, H., 1954-1958
      - Merrill, A., 1954-1955 (Box 166)
      - Reyneri, C., 1954
      - Rosenberg, E., 1954
      - Ungar, F., 1954-1956
    - 1955
      - Research reports
      - Alexander, G., 1955-1956
      - Carr, H. E., 1955-1956
      - El-Attar, Tawfik, 1955-1959
      - Elmadjian, Fred, 1955-1958
      - Feldstein, A., 1955-1958
      - Fridhandler, L., 1955-1958
      - Hafez, E. S. E., 1955-1956 (Box 167)
      - Hope, J., 1955-1957
      - Jacobsen, R., 1955-1957
      - Koritz, S. B., 1955
      - McNiven, N., 1955-1958
      - Merrill, A., 1955-1958
      - Rosemberg, 1955-1958
      - Rubin, B., 1955-1956
      - Saba, N., 1955
      - Slocombe, A., 1955
      - Todd, D., 1955-1956 (Box 168)
      - Wolf, M., 1955-1956
      - Zarrow, M. V., 1955-1956
    - 1956
      - Research reports
      - Air force, 1956
      - Dorfman, R., 1956-1958
      - Gibree, N., 1956-1958
      - Miyake, T., 1956-1958
    - 1957
      - Research reports
      - Kosaka, M., 1957
      - Lin Tsai, 1957-1958
      - Resnick, O., 1957-1958
      - Riano, M., 1957-1958
      - Robinson, K., 1957
    - 1958 (Box 169)
      - Research reports
      - Chang, M. C., 1958
      - Hechter, O., 1958
      - Saito, A., 1958-1959
    - 1959-1960
      - Research reports
      - Gesensway, S., 1959-1960
      - Hadd, H. E,. 1959-1960
      - Nakamura, E., 1959-1960
    - 1960, Albers, H., 1960
    - 1962
      - France, E. S., 1962-1963
      - Gestouid, (2 folders)
    - Undated
      - Ketosteroids
      - Korea data
      - Koritiz, S.B.
  - Unidentified
- Notebooks, 1949-1963 (Box 170-202)
  Laboratory notebooks.
  - Notebooks (Box 170)
    - 1) 1949-1950
    - 2-3) 1950
    - 4) 1951
    - 5) Androgens, 1951
    - 6) ACTH, 1951
    - 7) Smears, 1951 (Box 171)
    - 8) Glycogen, 1951
    - 9) Running wheels, 1952
    - 10) Androgens (muscles), 1952
    - 11) Thymus, 1952 (Box 172)
    - 12) Glycogen, 1953
    - 13) Androgen (muscles), 1953
    - 14) Thymus, 1953
    - 15) Estrogen (Box 173)
    - 16) Androgen (muscles), 1953
    - 17) Thymus, 1954
    - 18) Androgen (muscles), 1954
    - 19a) Fertility (rabbits), 1953 (Box 174)
    - 19b) Rosin-wounds-hair, 1954
    - 20) Androgen (muscles), 1954
    - 21) Androgen (muscles), 1955
    - 22) Rabbits, 1955 (Box 175)
    - 23) FSH-LH, 1955
    - 24) Androgen (muscles), 1955
    - 25a) Rat smears, 1955
    - 25b) Wounds, 1956 (Box 176)
    - 26) Androgen (muscles), 1956
    - 27a) Deciduoma, 1955
    - 27b) Sperm, 1956
    - 28) Thymus, 1956 (Box 177)
    - 29) Rabbits, 1956
    - 30) Government assay Q, 1956
    - 31) Government assay Q-17a, 1956
    - 32) Government assay Q-1s, preliminary, 1956 (Box 178)
    - 33) Government assay Q-17, 1956
    - 34) Government assay I, preliminary, 1957
    - 35a) Babies, 1954
    - 35b) Androgen, syntex, 1957 (Box 179)
    - 36) Progesterone and frog Hooker-Forbes
    - 37) Government Q-1, 1957
    - 38) Data, Miyake, T., 1956
    - 39) Government Q-17a, 1957 (Box 180)
    - 40) Government Q-17, 1957
    - 41) Government Q-17, 1957
    - 42) Government Q-1 Quant, 1957
    - 43) Parabiosis, 1958 (Box 181)
    - 44) Rabbits, 1959
    - 45) Parabiosis-mice, 1959
    - 46) Androgens (muscle, mice and insulin), 1954
    - 47) Screens (anti-infl.) 1953 (Box 182)
    - 48) Pre-Dee, 1954
    - 49) Smears-Rock, John 1953
    - 50) Smears-Rock, John
    - 51) Smears-Rock, John 1957 (Box 183)
    - 52) Nakamura, 1952
    - 53) Smears-WSH, 1956 (A-N)
    - 54) Smears-WSH, 1956 (O-Z)
    - 55) Smears, 1958 (Box 184)
    - 56) Carbonic anhydrase (rabbits)
    - 57) Carbonic anhydrase calculations, 1958
    - 58) Parabiosis (rats), 1959
    - 59) Carbonic anhydrase, 1959 (Box 185)
    - 60 Rope climbing, 1959
    - 61) Rabbits, 1959
    - 62) Balance book, 1960
    - 63) Cholesterol, 1959 (Box 186)
    - 64) Androgen (muscles), 1960
    - 65) Estrogen, 1960
    - 66) No volume
    - 67) Rabbits, 1960
    - 68) Carbonic anhydrase, 1960 (Box 187)
    - 69) Perfusion, 1961
    - 70) Kitgawa, 1960
    - 71) Rabbits, 1961
    - 72) Franch compounds, 1961 (Box 188)
    - 73) Rabbits, 1961
    - 74) Mouse super ovulation, 1961
    - 75) Carbonic anhydrase calculations, 1961
    - 76) Lakshman, 1961 (Box 189)
    - 77) Rabbits, 1962
    - 78) No volume
    - 79) Combe Chemical, Inc.
    - 80) Perfusion, 1963
    - 81) Carbonic anhydrase, 1963 (Box 190)
    - 82) Sperm (rats), 1964
    - 83) Ovaries, 1963
    - 84) Haiti and Puerto Rico, 1963
    - 85) Estrogen, 1965 (Box 191)
    - 86) Androgens (rats), 1965
    - 87) Progestrogen, 1965
    - 88) Chick androgen, 1965
    - 89) Palp book, 1965 (Box 192)
    - 90) Control mates (rabbits), 1965
    - 91a) Rat anti-implant, 1965
    - 91b) Puerto Rico and Haiti, Dec. 1965
    - 92) Puerto Rico and Haiti, Dec. 1965
    - 93) Puerto Rico and Haiti, Dec. 1965 (Box 193)
    - 94) Rabbits, 1966
    - 95) Combe Chemical, Inc.
    - 96) A/G Ratios, 1966
    - 97a) Puerto Rico and Haiti, 1961
    - 97b) Rabbit sperm, 1966 (Box 194)
    - 98) Puerto Rico and Haiti, 1963
    - 99) Puerto Rico and Haiti, 1966
    - 100) Prothrombius urines (Puerto Rico and Haiti), 1966
    - 101) Puerto Rico and Haiti, Dec. 1966
    - 102) Puerto Rico and Haiti, Dec. 1966
    - 103) Rabbit sperm, 1967 (Box 195)
    - 104) No volume
    - 105) Kobayashi, 1967
  - Pap smears
    - 1) Boston, Haiti, Humacao Mexico, Rio Piedras, Texas, 1960-1961
    - 2) Boston, Haiti, Humacao Mexico, Rio Piedras, Texas, 1961-1962
    - 3) Boston, Mexico, Texas, 1962-1964 (Box 196)
    - 4) Haiti (1), 1962-1964
    - 5) Haiti (2), 1964-1966
    - 6) Haiti (3), 1966-1966 (Box 197)
    - 7) Haiti (4), 1968
    - 8) Ceylon (1), 1961-1966
    - 9) Ceylon (2), 1966-1968
    - 10) Ponce, Pureto Rico (1), 1964-1966 (Box 198)
    - 11) Ponce, Puerto Rico (2), 1966-1968
    - 12) Ponce, Puerto Rico (3), 1968
    - 13) Caguas, Puerto Rico, 1963-1968
    - 14) Castaner, Pureto Rico, 1965 (Box 199)
    - 15) Rio Piedras, Puerto Rico (1), 1962-1964
    - 16) Rio Piedras, Puerto Rico (2) 1964-1965
    - 17) Rio Piedras, Puerto Rico (3), 1965-1966
    - 18) Rio Piedras, Puerto Rico (4), 1966-1967 (Box 200)
    - 19) Rio Piedras, Puerto Rico (5), 1967-1968
    - 20) Humacao, Puerto Rico (1), 1962-1963
    - 21) Humacao, Puerto Rico (2), 1963-1965
    - 22) Humacao, Puerto Rico (3), 1965-1966 (Box 201)
    - 23) Humacao, Puerto Rico (4), 1966-1968
  - Biopsies
    - 1) 1961-1963
    - 2) 1962-1963
    - 3) 1960-1963 (Box 202)
    - 4) 1962-1963
    - No number Human carbonic anhydrase, 1961
- Financial Papers, 1939-1967 (Box 203)
  Financial statements of the Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology and bills, statements, and correspondence relating to personal financial matters.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Bills, statements, forms, etc., 1954-1958 (Box 203)
  - Correspondence re personal financial matters, 1956-1963
  - Grant accounts, 1939-1942
  - Financial reports of Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology, 1944-1963
- Miscellany, 1923-1989 (Box 204-213)
  Awards, biographical material, family correspondence, memoranda, financial papers, notes, photographs, transcripts, writings, estate material, printed matter, and other miscellaneous items.
  - Awards (2 folders and 2 items) (Box 204)
  - Biographical material
  - Clippings regarding death of Pincus, Aug. 1967
  - Gregory Pincus Memorial Endowment Fund
  - Memorial resolutions
  - Miscellaneous
  - National Survey of Professional Scientific Salaries, 1947
  - Passports
  - Photographs of human eggs
  - Pincus estate
  - Plans for proposed labs for Worcester City Hospital, 1961
  - Printed matter
  - Printed matter, reprints of articles by Pincus (Box 205-206)
  - Printed matter (Box 207)
  - Replies to ad for "Houseman," 1963
  - Awards and certificates (Box OV 208)
  - Diaries, 1950-1967, (2 folders) (Box 209)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1940-1968, undated, (9 folders)
  - Special correspondence (Jean Boes), 1956-1957, (3 folders) (Box 210)
  - Financial records, personal
    - 1956-1957, (3 folders)
    - 1961-1967, (6 folders) (Box 211)
  - Other material (Box 212)
    - Address books, (3 vols.)
    - Awards, certificates, and transcripts, 1925-1967
    - Estate matters, death of Pincus, 1967-1968, (2 folders)
    - "Memories about Gregory Pincus," by Alexis G. Pincus, 1989
    - Newspaper clippings
    - Photographs
    - Research and writings by Pincus (Box 213)
      - Biographical, 1959-1966, undated
      - Control of Fertility, various material, undated
      - Poetry
- Addition, 1922-2006 (Box 214-216)
  Writings, correspondence, glass slides, notebook, scrapbook, and other papers.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material.
  - Award, certificates, medal, and sketches, 1965, 2006, undated (Box OV 214)
  - Glass slides, circa 1957 (Box OV 215)
  - Effect of an antiprogesterone steroid in women, undated (Box 216)
  - "Memories about Gregory Pincus," by Alexis G. Pincus, 1989
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1932-1939, 1967, undated
  - Miscellany, 1922, 1945, 1952, 1967-1978, 1985-1987, 1995-2001
  - Newspaper clippings about Pincus, 1945, 1967-1968
  - Notebook, undated
  - Pincus lab in France, 1989-1994
  - Scrapbook, 1963
  - Writings, undated